Ashley Scillitoe PhD

Researcher using data-driven methods to tackle problems in fluid dynamics, computational simulation, and engineering design.

London, UK $\bigcirc +44 (0)7926 251 138$ ⊠ ashleyscillitoe@googlemail.com ② ascillitoe.com



For detailed project descriptions, demonstration apps, and a list of publications, please visit ascillitoe.com.

Kev Skills

Programming HPC in Fortran with MPI/OpenMP/ Development HTML/CSS, Git version control, CI Coarrays, C++, Python, Matlab.

Theory

Computational PDE's, Linear algebra, supervised learning, dimension reduction, parallel computing, uncertainty quantification, feature engineering, black-box model interpretation.

and unit testing.

Other Python data stack (e.g. Scipy, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, PyTorch, PyMC3), Web apps (Dash/Plotly/Streamlit), Cloud computing (Azure and Heroku), LATEX.

Experience

Research

2018-present Research Associate, Data-Centric Aeronautics, The Alan Turing Institute, UK.

Researching novel data-centric techniques for tackling challenges in the aeronautical industry, with a focus on interpretability and uncertainty quantification. Projects include:

- Introduced polynomial regression trees; a new class of supervised machine learning models offering high interpretability, explainability, and accuracy.
- Used Mondrian forests to augment complex physical models with flow physics learnt from high fidelity simulations.
- Developed data-driven dimension reduction techniques for aerospace design tasks.
- Created rapid flowfield estimation frameworks using deep learning and dimension reduction.

2019-present **Developer**, Effective Quadratures, UK.

Developing machine learning capabilities in equadratures; an open source python library using polynomials for surrogate modelling, sensitivity analysis, and uncertainty quantification.

2019-present

Workshop Leader, Effective Quadratures, UK.

Prepare and run workshops on statistics and machine learning for engineers at the Culham Centre for Fusion Energy, Rolls-Royce, NPL, McLaren Automotive, Siemens, R^2 Data Labs and others.

2019-present Mentor, Google Summer of Code, Worldwide.

Mentor students on open source projects as part of GSoC, with previous projects including:

- Implementation of polynomial regression trees in equadratures.
- Building a web app for uncertainty quantification of physical systems.

2017-2018 Research Associate, University of Cambridge/Rolls Royce plc, UK.

- Worked with Rolls-Royce to bring PhD work into their production CFD code.
- Implemented a turbulence modelling uncertainty quantification framework in the code.

2011 Research Assistant, University of Manchester, UK.

Built upon MEng dissertation work, designing a propulsion system for a Hexrotor MAV. Designed a static thrust test rig and DAQ system. Frequently used CAD and rapid prototyping (SLA).

Conference Organisation

- 2020, 2021 Programme Committee, CFDML Workshop at ISC 2020 and 2021, Virtual.
 - 2015 **Deputy Coordinator**, Fluids Energy Turbo Expo 2015, Cambridge, UK. Industry
- 2011-2012 **Aerodynamics Intern**, *AgustaWestland Ltd*, Yeovil, UK.

 A one year internship split between the Wind Tunnel Test and Fuselage aerodynamics departments.

 Responsible for all aspects of a drag reduction test regime for the AW159 helicopter, and performed CFD analyses to design a new exhaust system.
 - 2010 Systems Engineering Summer Intern, Thales Air Defence Ltd, Belfast, UK.

 Created a Matlab/Simulink identification platform to identify black-box mathematical models of dynamical systems. This was then used to analyse and pre-process flight trial data.

Education

2013-2017 PhD - Computational Fluid Dynamics, University of Cambridge, UK.

Supervised by Professor Paul Tucker and supported by Rolls-Royce Aerospace.

- Examined the application of Large Eddy Simulation (LES) to modern gas turbine compressors.
- High fidelity LES used to study the complex flow physics in compressors, with findings informing compressor-specific turbulence modelling strategies.
- 2008-2013 MEng (Hons) Aerospace Engineering 1st Class, University of Manchester, UK. Graduated top of class with an 84% average. Elected student representative.
- 2001-2008 Fortismere School, London, UK.

Interests and Hobbies

Societies Active Affiliate of RAeS and AIAA.

Sport Competitive road cyclist, ski mountaineer, and qualified swimming teacher.

Publications

A selection of recent publications are shown below. For a complete list, please see ascillitoe.com.

- 2021 Scillitoe, A., Seshadri, P., Girolami, M. "Uncertainty Quantification for Data-Driven Turbulence Modelling with Mondrian Forests". *J. Comput. Phys.*. DOI.
- 2021 Scillitoe, A., Wong, C., Seshadri, P., Duncan, A. "Polynomial Ridge Flowfield Estimation". *Phys. Fluids. Under review.* PDF.
- 2021 Scillitoe, A., Wong, C., Hill, B., Seshadri, P. "Polynomial Regression Trees". *JMLR. Under review*.
- 2021 Scillitoe, A., Seshadri, P., Wong, C. "Instantaneous Flowfield Estimation with Gaussian Ridges". AIAA SciTech. DOI.
- 2020 Scillitoe, A., Ubald, B., Seshadri, P., Shahpar, S. "Design space exploration of stagnation temperature probes through dimension reducing subspaces". *ASME Turbo Expo.* DOI.
- 2019 Scillitoe, A., Tucker, P. G., Adami, P. "Large Eddy Simulation of Boundary Layer Transition Mechanisms in Gas-Turbine Compressor Cascades". *J. Turbomach.* DOI.